[INTRO] There are three things to be concerned about in BBP posture. The first one is...
[INTRO] Because the upper body is in this completely open position...
[INTRO] You should not ride with the feeling of leaning forward...
[INTRO] In the case of heel side turn, the direction of the turn
and the direction of the pelvis rotation are the same...
[INTRO] I will show you the tip I gave you a while ago on the slope...
Hello, I'm Seung Won Kim
Now, I'm going to start about Basic Carving.
Basic carving is
You learned BBP posture before.
Highest BBP posture, That is the legs are almost straight.
At this time, you shouldn't try to stretch your legs too much,
If you can't stretch your legs because the highback restrains you from it, take a bent position
bend your rear leg this much, just stand in the center of the deck.
Anyway, take the BBP posture as high as possible,
as I said previously, the pelvic rotation,
rather than pushing the rear leg in,
Actually rotate the pelvis,
Find the feeling of turning the pelvis rather than
the feeling of turning through the upper body.
Even if your upper body stays still,
pelvic rotation is recommended.
There are three things to be concerned about in BBP posture.
The first one is 'Inclination'.
Inclination is ...
Riders using duck stance ride with the upper body closed like this generally,
looking from the side
As they ride with the upper body closed like this,
they will give the tilt onto the belly or chest.
Heel turn is performed onto one's back.
Due to the upper body being in completely open position in the Forward Carving,
you shouldn't ride with the feeling of leaning forward.
As the pelvis is rotated like this,
the correct way is to make the inclination with the feeling
of going over the front right side of the pelvis.
In the case of a heel, you should make tilt onto left back side of the pelvis
or feeling like you are leaning to the left shoulder direction.
If you don't do that, you will slip during carving.
So, it is important that you make inclination correctly to prevent slipping.
The second is sight directing.
Actually, if you have been snowboarding for years,
you will ride well even if you don't care about sight directing.
Basically, I recommend you the sight direction is directed towards the nose
or the actual direction you're going to.
But you don't have to ride like this,
if you slip when you begin heel side turn,
it might be a matter of overrotating the deck.
Even if you direct your properly straight forward,
in order to prevent the deck from turning,
directing your sight a little more to the right,
might prevent the heel side slip when you enter the heel side turn
Likewise, toe side turn is the same.
If you slip when edging the toe side,
do not rotate your sight in the direction of the deck.
If you begin the turn while keeping your sight at the fence you saw when you did edge changing,
(translator comment: there is a fence on both sides of the slopes in Korea,
the author means: keep your sight a little bit longer to the left)
you might prevent slipping.
Like this, the sight direction is basically looking forward,
if you make direction according to the symptoms of the problem,
I think you might be helpful to fix it.
And the third is pelvic rotation.
In general, when you ride for basic carving,
even if you don?™t care much about pelvic rotation in the case of toe side turn,
the pelvis does not loosen easily.
Because in the case of toe side turn,
the turn rotation is the right direction in case of the regular,
and the pelvis is turned to the left by the turn itself.
So, because the direction to rotate is opposite to each other, left and right,
the pelvis might be rotated naturally even if you don?™t put attention at it.
In the case of heel side turn,
because the direction in which you want to rotate the pelvis and the turn direction of the deck are same,
if heel side begining position is like this,
and if you don't keep actively rotating the pelvis,
the pelvis will loosen like this as turn progresses.
As we make keep rotating until finish like this when we make sliding turn,
in the case of basic carving,
to point where the deck doesn't slip due to excess,
you have to keep pay attention to rotate the upper body until heel turn is finished after edgging,
then you can complete heel basic carving without pelvis loosened.
Now, I will tell you again through practice.
I'll show you now.
three things I mentioned earlier. First is inclination. You have to lean body to the edge accurately.
Second is eyes sight. You look straight forward.
Last is the pelvic rotation.
You have to perform the pelvis rotation in the heel side turn like this.
You should begin the basic carving with pelvis rotation.
I will show you
Inclination
Sight
Pelvis
Inclination
Sight
Pelvis
This slop has high angle,
so I'm getting pretty fast now.
As you can see, the pelvis should not be loosened while making a turn.
The basic carving should be done in state of the upper body still open like this,
At this time, you should not only open the upper body,
you have to open the pelvis correctly.
A good tip to check this while riding yourself is
put your hands on the pelvis like this.
Actually, there are some people who use the cross as a gesture when doing basic carving.
And some people do like this
But it doesn?™t matter much.
You just do comfortable depending on the situation.
To check if the pelvis is open when you do basic carving,
The most accurate method is putting your hands over the pelvis like this
Sometimes when one rides with arms stretched to sides like this,
his/hers upper body is rotated but the pelvis does not open correctly.
So, rather than checking it like this,
hands on the pelvis,
and turning like this,
I recommend to ride with checking the pelvic rotation.
I will try again while with hands on.
Heel side
Pelvic rotation
Inclination
Toe side is easy.
Pay more attention to pelvic rotation when making a heel side turn.
Heel side
Pelvic rotation
This slope has high angle,
And I am on a deck with a turn radius of 12 meters.
So, speed is rising fast.
You guys don't take a deck with too big radius.
If possible, a round deck or a little small size radius..
It is recommended that you take a deck with a shorter side cut like Desperado of Gray corporation.
Let's go down
Have you practiced?
If you try it, it might not go as you think.
Pelvic rotation is not as easy as you think
So I will give you a practice TIP.
All the students I teach practice this method a lot.
The method is....
when you practice,
you could not ride basic on advanced slope due to too fast.
Don't try to do basic carving in that slope,
you just do side slipping.
How to do it?
You make BBP Posture...
Because you are practicing basic carving,
you don't lower your upper body too much,
you think you are doing basic carving now,
you come down to side sliping only.
If you do side slip like this,
Pelvic rotation is actually hard to keep while balancing.
So when you doing side sliping,
if you have a feeling of doing a pelvic rotation while standing on the heel edge
it's practically same as heel side turn when doing basic carving.
It's just not turning.
The balance needed for your body is same between heelside sliping and basic carving.
So, you can practice through heelside sliping
You do the pelvic rotation while doing side sliping like this.
Put your hand on the pelvis to see how rotate my pelvis when you have pelvic rotation,
Make rotation,
and direct your eye sight forward,
then you ride down like this.
Now when you ride down like this, if the deck rotate to the other side,
or if deck rotate to the right side,
The your weight balance is not proper.
Exactly put on centered weight point..
Put the weight on the center of the deck,
LG: the same as previous line
While preventing the deck from rotating either way,
keep the pelvis rotation,
you should take side sliping straight.
It's the same for both the toe side and heel side.
Actually, most people are good in case of toe side.
Because everyone is good at toe basic carving.
Because heel side sliping doesn't work well,
Please practice side sliping with care for pelvic rotation.
That way, obviously,
heel basic carving will be good.
I'll show you the TIP told you about on the slope
Let me show you first toe side sliping.
Open the upper body on the toe side too,
and with the pelvis rotated, side sliping as it is.
Toe turn is usually good,
but, some people may not be able to open like this
Anyway, while doing toe side sliping,
keeping the deck doesn't rotate this side,
keeping doesn't rotate to the other side,
LG: the same line as above
you are practicing the balance straight down.
Then, most important heel side.
I'll show you heel side sliping.
Heel side sliping will be a little difficult.
So, most people wouldn't do well with heel side with heel side sliping.
Surely, when heel side sliping goes down first time,
The pelvis will closed like this.
We have opened a lot of pelvis on the plain before,
It opened well.
But, when you come to the slope, the pelvis is closed like this.
In this case,
do side sliping like this..
(Come this way)
You open the pelvis like this while doing side sliping.
Like this
Again
While doing side sliping straight,
and open pelvis like this,
do not bias the side slip to either side,
It just goes down.
Pelvis rotation.
Pelvis rotation like this.
Now, you don't this by gathering your knees.
Gathering your knees has no meaning.
I have to rotate the pelvis like this ...
Yes it's over
Some of you may not be able to easily do basic carving.
For those who have never tried carving,
or for those who have a hard time adjusting to speed,
I think it would be a good idea to do the following exercises
First,
if you are not sure about feeling of the edging of the carving,
you pactice the traverse on the slope with high angle like this,
Traverse.. Traverse means to ride in the direction the deck edge is pointing.
So, deck is not going down with slip like this as much as possible,
so that you can use only the edge to move,
go straight in the direction that the deck points to,
then change edge to the toe side,
Also, go straight in the direction that the deck points to,
I'm pointing the deck
Where I'm leaning
I'm riding while feeling myself
Then I'll show you the traverse
Now heelside
Now when traverse like this
To avoid slipping as much as possible
Stand up so as to avoid slipping as much as possible.
You shouldn't slip like this when riding.
When riding
Now, let me show you the side
Now like this
Not until J-turn
Not until J-turn, but as far as possible
You can practice traverse
If you say that you feel like you've learned the feeling
Then practice J-turn once
Then it's good to draw the letter S once
In the case of J-turn,
if you've gotten some edge feel,
you should turn the deck in the direction of the fall line.
Then, you should ride flat down for a short time..
You should little ride flat before the speed goes too high,
then make inclination and you practice basic carving
Now, let me show you the heelside J turn first
As I taught you, do the pelvis rotation as much as possible
heel
Now, I'll show you toe too.
Now toe ...
LG: same as previous line ??
KIM : yes. I'm demonstrating.
Open the pelvis
Toe side
Now you can ride while drawing a J-turn like this
I slipped a little earlier, but I'll show you again.
Open the pelvis and stay
Now, down the slop in the shape of a J
So that we can go up a little
If you set up the blade properly, it will be shaped like a J
You will be able to climb the slopes.
However, when you do this, there is a situation of reverse driving
Where there are no people
If there is someone on the slope, you need to check the top of the slope.
You have to be careful not to have an accident.
Please be careful
After practicing this once, S shape of basic carving
Please practice properly
Thank you